<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ProtosArt</title>
    <description>Organic Abstraction</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 21:12:11 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 21:12:11 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Beginning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your interest in ProtosArt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ProtosArt comes from the greek work proto, or first.  Fractal artwork has long been admired, without completely understanding the geometry behind it.  The golden rectangle of Greek design is a prime example - the same rectangle in ever increasing or decreasing sizes formed the basis of all proportions of Greek art.  Sacred Geometry of Buddist Mandalas is another example of these repeating mathmatical patterns and greater or lesser scales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fractals are found everywhere, from a honeycomb, to a nautilus shells, trees, mountains, rivers, even the human body.  It is for this reason why, despite the abstract nature, there is an organic feel and appeal to fractal geomety and fractal artwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complex, and yet able to appear minimalist, fractal geometry in it’s greater and larger forms is increasingly difficult to render without the aid of a computer.  My methods include several different programs which approach the mathmatics in unique ways, and I am always looking at other ideas and aesthetics to continue and grow my abilities and my own repertoire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typical time to create artwork is upwards of a week per piece.  Generally I am able to find the feel of a piece on the first day, getting the form and adjusting color.  Then a computer is needed to crunch the complex mathmatics of rendering, which days anywhere from one day to a week, depending on how complex and large the initial rendering is.  Extremely large pieces are done in stripes - strips that are then manipulated and patched together like panaramic artwork often is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sort of creativity really appeals to my loves.  Science, all sorts of science, has always been a deep interest of mine.  Art has always been another interest, photography especially.  As I was searching for creative outlets, I stumbled upon this particular form of art and fell instantly in love - able to satisfy my creative desires, as well as my scientific curiousity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 19:06:27 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/journal/The_Beginning/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/journal/The_Beginning/</guid>
        
        
        <category>site</category>
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
